# Lina Sakhneny

## PHD Medical Science | Data Analyst Expert

Telephone: +972526998605 | Email: <u>linasakh17@gmail.com</u>| Israel

## **Summary**

More than 9 years experiment in medical field, biotech and HealthCare AI companies. Experienced in hand-on experience (*in-vivo and in-vitro*) research science field design and conduct investigative. Skilled in project management, Strategic planning, including budget management, artificial intelligent, team leading, project design, development, medical writing, and data analysis(SQL, Python, Power BI, Excel). Excellent self-learning, Self-motivated and seeks opportunities to continue learning and growing. Work in multidisciplinary teams with with the business development department, QA, medical scientists, and other professionals.

## **Skills:**

- Project and data operation leading
- Provide technical and scientific guidance to the staff.
- Support AI model development
- Data analysis (SQL, Python, Power BI, Excel)
- Collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams (BD, researchers, algorithmic, AI and ML teams)
- Manage and coordinate all phases of the study/ project process.
- Experiment planning, protocol design and development.
- Generate high-quality study plans and reports.
- Analyzing and interpretation of the results with the highest scientific standards
- Well organized detail oriented
- Provide excellent customer service.

## More lab Skills

- Protein: Immunohistochemistry, immunofluorescence.
- Histology: Tissue harvest, embedding process, Tissue sectioning, Staining processes.
- Tissue culture: Cell growth in culture (primary culture, cell lines), utilizing sterile technique.
- Biochemistry: ELISA, Western Blotting.
- Molecular biology: RNA extraction, PCR, RT/qPCR.
- Worked with: Fluoresceine, Light and Confocal microscopy, Flow cytometry (FACS), FACS sorting, Cryostat, Microtome, Tissue processing.
- Animal Handling: Mouse handling, tissue harvest, islets of Langerhans isolation, physiological experiment, in vivo skills, IP/SC injections, tail blood withdrawal.
- Software: Kaluza, GraphPad Prism, ImageJ, Photoshop, Illustrator.

## **Work Experience**

Feb. 2023 – present

## Project and Data Lead NucleAI, Israel

Nucleai is a Biotech company that leverages AI and spatial biology to analyze tissue samples, helping to advance precision medicine and improve cancer diagnosis and treatment outcomes

- Leading a team internally
- Responsible for the project end-to-end, Strategic planning, oversee the day-to-day work on projects while managing the work of the project task force, assuring that all team members are aligned with the project's goals.
- Testing and improving the Data process, development new capabilities
- Work internally with multi-disciplinary teams to oversee and manage operations (scientific, algorithmic, AI and ML teams)
- Lead conversations with leading pathologists.
- Own the entire data of the project: collecting the data, characterizing it, performing QC, deciding on annotation strategies, Training the data team, preparing, and maintaining a landing page for the project
- Pathology outlines self-learning, data collection.
- Oversee activities, needs, and bottlenecks to ensure delivery within timelines and key milestones.

# Feb. 2022- Feb. 2023 Study Director/ Project Manager Pharmaseed LTD, Israel.

A GLP-certified preclinical and early clinical CRO, providing preclinical, early clinical, and consulting services for medical device, biotechnology, and pharmaceutical companies

- Manage and coordinate all phases of the study process, process task prioritization and close supervision of multidisciplinary projects including troubleshooting and customer retention
- Generate high-quality study plans, reports, analyzing and interpretation of the results with the highest scientific standards
- Provide technical and scientific guidance to the research staff
- Collaborate with the Business Development team
- Multi-interface work, both internally, with the business development department, QA department and the financial department, and externally with suppliers, service providers and collaborators.

#### Aug. 2014- Sep .2021 Research Assistant

# Tel-Aviv University, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Department of Cell and Developmental Biology

- Manage and coordinate all phases of the study process
- Experiment planning and conducting
- Conduct literature reviews
- Collect and analyze data
- Guide and train new students in the lab
- Calibrate and write new protocols
- Lab maintenance

## **Teaching Experience**

## Oct. 2017-Sep. 2021 Teaching Assistant

Tel-Aviv University, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Department of Cell and Developmental Biology

Courses: Histology and Embryology, 2<sup>nd</sup> year medical students

## **Education**

## 2024

## **Data Analyst Expert**

John Bryce Academy

- Database structures
- Basic data analyst using SQL
- Advances SQL for data analyst
- Developing program using MSSQL
- Python basics
- Data analysis with pandas
- DA using AI
- Data analysis using Excel
- Power BI
- Introduction to big data analysis

#### 2017-2021

#### Ph.D., Medical Sciences

Department of Cell and Developmental Biology,

Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.

Thesis: The Molecular Basis of Pericyte-Dependent  $\beta$ -Cell Function: Elucidating the Roles of Pericytic Tcf7l2, BMP4, and Basement Membranes Components

#### 2014-2016

## M.Sc., Medical Sciences

Department of Cell and Developmental Biology,

Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel

Thesis: Studying the Role of Islet Pericytes in beta-Cell Function and Glucose Homeostasis.

## **July 2014**

## **CRA-Clinical Research Associated Training Course**

- IHC-GCP
- Legal and regulatory requirements: Israel ministry of health, EMA, FDA
- Monitoring and coordination of clinical trails and projects
- Clinical trials in medical devices
- Ethics in clinical trials
- Safety and Pharmacovigilance
- The investigator and the sponsor
- Quality and Statistics

#### 2010-2014

## **B.Sc.**, Medical and Life sciences

Sackler Faculty of Medicine and Wise Faculty of Life Sciences, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel

#### Language:

Arabic – Native

English – Fluent

Hebrew – Fluent

# **Appendix**

## **Honors and Awards**

2021	Award for excellent students for scientific achievements in Developmental Biology, awarded by The Switzerland Institute of Developmental Biology
2019	Prize for excellent Israeli-Arab Ph.D female students, awarded by the Babcom Center.
2019	The Constantiner travel fellowship for Ph.D. student, awarded by the George S. Wise Faculty of Life Sciences and the Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University.
2018-2021	The Zvi Yanai Scholarship for Israeli Arab, Druze and Circassians Ph.D. students, awarded by State of Israel Ministry of Science and Technology.
2018	A scholarship from the program of excellent Ph.D. students in the Arabic and minority populations, awarded by the Israel Council for Higher Education.
2018	Prize for excellence in Ph.D. studies, awarded by the department of Cells and Developmental Biology, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University.
2018	Prize for excellence student based on scientific publications from Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University.

## **Conferences presentation**

Oral presentations:

2021 <u>Sakhneny L.</u> Muller L, Schonblum A, Azaria S, Burganova G, Epshtein A, Spagnoli

FA, and Landsman L. The postnatal pancreatic microenvironment guides beta-cell maturation through BMP4 production.

TAU-EPFL Symposium on Developmental Biology, the Switzerland Institute of Developmental Biology, Tel Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel

## Poster presentation:

2019 Sakhneny L, Schonblum A, Azaria S, Harari N, Epshtein A, and Landsman L. Pericytic

BMP4 is Required for Glucose-Stimulated Insulin Secretion.

The 3rd Joint Meeting of the EASD-ISG & Beta-cell Workshop, Oxford, England.

2018 Sakhneny L, Rachi E, Epshtein A, Guez HC, Wald-Altman S, Lisnyansky M, Khalifa-

Malka L, Hazan A, Baer D, Priel A, Weil M, and Landsman L. Pancreatic Pericytes

Support β-Cell Function in a Tcf712-Dependent Manner.

The 8th D-Cure Annual Symposium Cross Talk and Innovation in Diabetes, Herzliya,

Israel.

2017 <u>Sakhneny L</u>, Rachi E, Epshtein A, Guez HC, Wald-Altman S, Lisnyansky, Weil M, and Landsman L. Elucidating the role of pancreatic pericytes in diabetes-associated β-cell dysfunction.

The 12<sup>th</sup> Research Day of the Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel

2017 Sakhneny L, Rachi E, Epshtein A, Guez HC, Wald-Altman S, Lisnyansky, Weil M, and Landsman L. Elucidating the role of pancreatic pericytes in diabetes-associated β-cell dysfunction.

Symposium on Development of Sensory Systems, the Switzerland Institute of Developmental Biology, Tel Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel

## **Publications:**

## Peer reviewed

1. Glorieux L, Sapala A, Willnow D, Moulis M, Salowka A, Darrigrand JF, Edri Sh, Schonblum A, Sakhneny L, Schaumann L, Gomez H, Lang Ch, Conrad L, Guillemot F, Levenberg Sh, Landsman L, Iber D, Pierreux Ch, and Spagnoli FA.

Development of a 3D atlas of the embryonic pancreas for topological and quantitative analysis of heterologous cell interactions

Development, In press

(Rank: Developmental biology 5/41, IF: 5.868)

2. Sakhneny L, Muller L, Schonblum A, Azaria S, Burganova G, Epshtein A, Spagnoli

FA, and Landsman L.

The postnatal pancreatic microenvironment guides beta-cell maturation through BMP4 production.

Developmental Cell 2021; 56(19): 2703-2711.e5

(Rank: Developmental biology 1/40, IF: 12.270)

3. Sakhneny L\*, Epshtein A\*, and Landsman L.

Pericytes contribute to the islet basement membranes to promote beta-cell gene expression.

Scientific Reports 2021;11(1):1-10.

(Rank: Multidisciplinary sciences 17/73, IF: 4.379)

\*First authorship shared

4. Nash Y, Ganoth A, Borenstein-Auerbacha N, Levy-Barazany H, Goldsmith G, Kopelevich A, Pozyuchenko K, <u>Sakhneny L</u>, Lazdon K, Blanga-Kanfi S, Alhadeff R, Benromano T, Landsman L, Tsfadia Y, and Frenkel D.

From virus to diabetes therapy: characterization of a specific insulin-degrading enzyme inhibitor for diabetes treatment.

FASEB journal, 2021; 35(5):e21374.

(Rank: Biochemistry and Molecular biology 84/298, IF: 5.191)

5. Harari N, <u>Sakhneny L</u>, Khalifa-Malka L, Busch A, Hertel K J, Hebrok M., and Landsman L. Pancreatic pericytes originate from the embryonic pancreatic mesenchyme.

Developmental Biology 2019. 449(1), 14–20

(Rank: Developmental Biology 15/41, IF: 3.582, Times cited:6)

6. <u>Sakhneny L</u>, Rachi E, Epshtein A, Guez HC, Wald-Altman S, Lisnyansky M, Khalifa-Malka L, Hazan A, Baer D, Priel A, Weil M, and Landsman L.

Pancreatic Pericytes Support β-Cell Function in a Tcf7l2-Dependent Manner.

Diabetes 2018;67(3), 437-447

(Rank: Endocrinology and Metabolism 11/145, IF: 9.461, Times cited: 20)

7. Epshtein A, Rachi E, Sakhneny L, Mizrachi S, Baer B, Landsman L.

Neonatal pancreatic pericytes support beta-cell proliferation.

Molecular Metabolism 2017;6(10):1330-1338.

(Rank: Endocrinology and Metabolism 16/145, IF: 7.424, Times cited: 12)

8. Epshtein A, Sakhneny L and Landsman L.

Isolating and Analyzing Cells of the Pancreas Mesenchyme by Flow-Cytometry.

Journal of Visualized Experiments 2017;(119):5-11

(Rank: Multidisciplinary Sciences 49/73, IF: 1.355, Times cited: 9)

9. Sasson, A.\*, Rachi, E.\*, <u>Sakhneny, L\*</u>, Baer, D., Lisnyansky, M., Epshtein, A. and Landsman, L. Islet Pericytes Are Required for Beta-cell Maturity. *Diabetes*. 2016; 65(10):3008-14.

The required for Bett cert Mattan B. 2464 B. 2010, 00 (10),000

(Rank: Endocrinology and Metabolism 11/145, IF: 9.461, Times cited: 33)

\*First authorship shared

## **Reviews**

1. Sakhneny L, Khalifa-Malka L, and Landsman L.

Pancreas organogenesis: approaches to elucidate the role of epithelial-mesenchymal interactions.

Seminar in Cell and Developmental Biology. 2019. 92, 89-96

(Rank: Developmental Biology 4/41, IF: 7.727, Times cited: 8)